# Sam Posner - Creative Coder

Web: smpsnr@outlook.com ● <a href="https://posner.zone">https://posner.zone</a>

Code: <a href="https://bitbucket.org/smpsnr">https://github.com/smpsnr</a>

#### **Profile**

Software developer with experience in creative, interdisciplinary, and experimental technology. Computer science educator and researcher. Graduate with BA in digital/electronic media from Pomona College.

Developer for mobile, web, and embedded platforms including ...... Android, iOS, .NET/Mono, HTML5, and Arduino

• Using technologies like ...... OpenCV, OpenGL, Cinder, and openFrameworks

### Work Experience

## ANDY CAVATORTA - Brooklyn, NY.....Summer of 2017

#### **Computer Vision Consultant**

Consulted on computer vision techniques for smart appliance project. Developed object detection and classification software with OpenCV and TensorFlow.

## MIDNIGHT COMMERCIAL – Brooklyn, NY......June 2016 – February 2017 Software Developer

Developed software to power technology innovation projects for clients including Google, Samsung, and Target. Worked on a project to visualize live tardigrades housed in a module for Google's Ara smartphone: developed a GPU-based microlens array reconstruction technique and an Android graphics backend for the user-facing app. For Samsung, developed an embedded camera system with OpenCV image processing for an Android-based IOT smart appliance. Worked primarily in C++ and Java.

# NETBURNER INC – San Diego, CA.....Summer of 2015

#### **Technology Evangelist Intern**

Designed and developed projects to showcase NetBurner's embedded HTTP technology, including a coin-operated Bitcoin vending machine and an Ethernet network traffic visualizer. Implemented projects in C++ and HTML5/JavaScript, and documented them in articles for the NetBurner website (<a href="http://netburner.com/blog/Sam-Posner">http://netburner.com/blog/Sam-Posner</a>).

## ST. LUKE'S SCHOOL and WATERSIDE SCHOOL – New Canaan, CT.....Summer of 2014 Engineering and Game Development Instructor

Helped run two summer programs on the St. Luke's campus: an engineering course for St. Luke's middle school students, and the Waterside elementary school game development course that I founded in 2011 (see Waterside School entry). Tutored engineering students on circuit design, 3D printing, and programming projects. Designed and taught Scratch game development classes.

# PICKVEE INC – San Francisco, CA......Summer of 2013 Web Development Contractor

Developed web-based mobile and desktop healthcare software. Designed and implemented SQL data model and application logic using Java Servlet and Google Web Toolkit. Worked closely with designer to implement user interface in HTML5 and CSS.

# Sam Posner

HIDDEN GENIUS PROJECT - Oakland, CASummer of 2013
Computer Science Instructor (Intern)
Worked with education entrepreneurs and activists in initiative to help black Oakland high school students achieve success in
technology. Taught computer science and Python programming: led classes, designed quizzes, and mentored students.
POMONA COLLEGE – Claremont, CA
Computer Science Teaching Assistant
Assisted professors in introductory and intermediate computer science classes: Introduction to Computer Science and Advanced
Programming and Data Structures. Ran lab sections, graded assignments, and offered mentor sessions.
WATERSIDE SCHOOL – Stamford, CTSummers of 2011 & 2012
Game Development Instructor
Proposed, designed, and taught a summer game development class for 3 <sup>rd</sup> , 4 <sup>th</sup> , and 5 <sup>th</sup> graders. Instructed students in basic programming and game design, emphasizing storytelling and interactivity.
Research Experience
POMONA COLLEGE and HARVEY MUDD COLLEGE – Claremont, CAFall 2014 – April 2015
Researcher
Conducted and published original research on Neo-Piagetian Reasoning and Abstraction: Introducing Low-Level Programming to Novice Students. See April 2015 issue of the Journal of Computing Sciences in Colleges: <a href="http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2752648">http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2752648</a> .
CLAREMONT GRADUATE UNIVERSITY – Claremont, CAWinter 2013 – Early 2014
Research Assistant
Assisted professor with web forum research project: developed software to scrape, parse, and visualize data from HTML. Delivered graphical and XML results.
Education
POMONA COLLEGE – Claremont, CA
BA in Media Studies with concentration in Digital and Electronic Media2016
• Collaborated with theater and CS professors on <i>Motionfeed</i> project: <a href="https://arcadeoftheabsurd.com/portfolio/motionfeed/">https://arcadeoftheabsurd.com/portfolio/motionfeed/</a>
• Completed thesis project deconstructing gender classification algorithms: <a href="https://arcadeoftheabsurd.com/portfolio/agpd">https://arcadeoftheabsurd.com/portfolio/agpd</a>
ST. LUKE'S SCHOOL – New Canaan, CT
STEM/Cum Laude Diploma
• Developed, evaluated, and presented an economic model of open source software development

 $\bullet \ \, \text{Studied and presented the importance of low-level systems knowledge to computer science education}$